IRINA DETOCKINA

A LINGUIST LOOKING TO PIVOT INTO TECH CAREER



CONTACT

Sydney Australia

irinadetochkina@protonmail.ch

https://www.irinadetochkina.link/



PROFILE

I graduated from my university with a Specialist (5 years of higher education) degree in Linguistics. Keen on semiotics, etymology and all things linguistics I, however, decided to help my parents with running a small car spare parts shop. After I got married, I moved 2 countries in 6 years, taking care of my family wellbeing while we were settling in. As my 2 kids grow older I now have more time for studying something I was always passionate about -- computer science and now am looking to secure a role in tech-information industry.

SKILLS

- Basic understanding of networking technologies (TCP/IP)
- Beginner level programming skills: C, Python, SQL
- Linux, can perform basic tasks in shell
- Knowledge of core AWS services and use cases, billing and pricing models, security concepts.
- HTML, CSS, Javascript

STRENGTHS

- Getting things done attitude.
- Team player and contributor.
- Diligence and attention to detail.
- Clear communicator in verbal and written English. Excellent written communication skills.
- Strong leadership skills: coaching and mentoring, decision making, problem solving, providing feedback.

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS

HARVARD'S CS50X: INTRODUCTION TO THE INTELLECTUAL ENTERPRISES OF COMPUTER SCIENCE AND THE ART OF PROGRAMMING DEC 2021

AWS ANZ USER GROUP MENTORSHIP AWARD OCT 2021

AWS CLOUD PRACTITIONER
AUG 2021

IRINA DETOCKINA

Sydney Australia

irinadetochkina@protonmail.ch

https://www.irinadetochkina.link/



EXPERIENCE

Mentor

AWS SheBuilds CloudUp program Sep 2021 — current

I enjoy mentoring 5000+ participants community, supporting women in their cloud journey. I provide SheBuilds team with valuable feedback which helps improving the workflows.

Teacher

Community Languages School Feb 2021 — May 2021

In this role I appreciated the challenge of building a learning course for my group of 8 students based on different programs and textbooks -- at my own whim. I was able to adjust methods and my expectations so that every kid enjoyed individualized approach, that helped them feel confident speaking a foreign language.

The feedback I received from parents proved I achieved the goal of involving kids in activities, which helped them learn the language; they got passionate about reading books in Russian.

Mum and household manager

Jan 2011 - current

Taking care of the family while moving 2 foreign countries in 6 years. Being a role model for 2 daughters, drawing my inspiration from watching them grow. That's a constant work in progress, of course.

Office manager

Europa-Avto, Krasnodar, Russian Federation Feb 2003 — Jan 2011

- Mail processing, recordkeeping, scheduling;
- budgeting, planning and optimization;
- process management and problem solving;
- negotiation and dealing with objections as a salesperson;
- leveraging emotional intelligence for better customer service;
- software and hardware troubleshooting;
- business automation software (1C:Enterprise): developing and customizing small enterprise solutions.

Opening a small family car spare shop with my parents, we've expanded our customer base tenfold within 3 years and helped launching several partnership businesses in Krasnodar region.

Working 8 years in a company of 12 employees my roles implied different kinds of responsibilities: from working directly with customers as a salesperson, through the warehouse management, all the way up to people management, and anything in between.

EDUCATION

Specialist in Linguistics, Teacher (5 years)

Kuban State University, Krasnodar, Russian Federation 1999-2004